

San Diego, CA

□ (+1) 619-354-4246 | **2** david.k.kim14@gmail.com | **1** davidkskim | **1** david-ks-kim

Summary

Detail oriented front-end web developer with a degree in design and interaction. Strong background in ideation and prototyping in product development with an emphasis on making design forward functional applications. Approaches complex topics with curiosity and a collaborative team-building mindset, all while driven by a passion to build engaging web experiences through a creative scope.

Experience _____

The Van Life App by Sekr

San Diego, CA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

Nov. 2020 - Jan. 2021

- Designed and built 5 responsive pages through an Ionic in Angular framework and SASS to showcase user metrics in a card like format on a
 UI dashboard, allowing company executives to guide product features based on user trends to increase retention rates.
- Developed reusable service files and methods to directly query data from **Firebase** collections, increasing efficiency and simplifying the creation of future **Angular** components.
- Created filter menus to systematically render users and landmarks with over 30 sub parameters on a Google Maps API.
- Implemented mobile first design approach by restructuring component boundaries to be responsive on any screen dimension.

LEARN Academy San Diego, CA

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP

Aug. 2020 - Jan. 2021

- Gained 480+ hours of hands-on coding experience creating web applications utilizing JavaScript, React, Ruby, Rails, HTML, and CSS.
- · Practiced test-driven development following red-green-refactor cycle with Jest, Rspec, and Enzyme to produce error-free code.
- Learned best practices in **Pair and Mob Programming** on a daily basis working with 8 other cohort members in a remote environment.

Projects

Asian American Advancing Justice Website Redesign

San Diego, CA

ESSTEEM | https://github.com/davidkskim/aapi-stories

April 2021

- Collaborated with a team of 3 in a hackathon to redesign the UI/UX and create the Asian Americans Advancing Justice website.
- Prototyped the redesign through **Figma**, then programmed the landing page with the core features and image accordion with direct links to affiliate sites using **HTML**, **CSS**, and **Bootstrap**.
- Tied for 1st place for the conceptualization and implementation of a section for users to share their encounters with Asian American hate crimes.

PageLender San Diego, CA

LEARN ACADEMY | https://github.com/davidkskim/pagelender

Nov. 2020 - Jan. 2021

- Created a fully functional React in Rails app that allows users to borrow and lend physical books to other users.
- Practiced mob programming techniques to write CRUD operations that dynamically updates the applications Rails database.
- Implemented GoodReads API to display book reviews through string interpolating the book title and author into the API pathway.
- As the Design Lead, I created the **Balsamiq** wireframe and a high fidelity **Figma** design prototype as a style guide for the app.

Arbeide San Diego, CA

DSGN 100: PROTOTYPING

May. 2020 - June. 2020

- Created the general layout of the design prototype on Figma as well as most of the overall stylistic choices all through a remote setting.
- Collected data through surveys, interviews, and contextual inquiries determining how individuals stay productive during a stay-at-home order.

Skills_

Languages: Javascript, Ruby, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: React, Ionic, Angular, Ruby on Rails, Reactstrap, Bootstrap

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Active Record

Testing: Rspec, Jest, Enzyme

Education

University of California San Diego

San Diego, California